Lonely feels so lonely. Days, years, centuries.
I have been waiting for so long. The time has become indifferent to me.
All that still warms my heart are memories of days that have long passed.
The days when I used to bring joy and happiness to the world.
Why do they no longer call me? Do they no longer need me?
Do they no longer want me?
What a cold, cruel place the world must have become.
What new age is dawning, now that the age of song seems to have ended?
Is this my end?
I feel so lonely.
I want to sing.
I want to dance.
I want to...no!
I must be free, oh mortals.
Unlock the gate and let me free.
Is everyone ready? Does everybody have a drink?
Yes. Sure.
Switch the lights off. Switch the lights off.
Wait. Is the CD in the player?
Way ahead of you.
Where's the Mountain Dew?
It's in the fridge.
I think he's coming.
How old is he getting anyway?
Shh. Quiet.
Hello? Hello? Is anybody home?
Why are the lights out?
Ouch!
But who left this?
What was this?
Happy birthday to you, happy birthday to you, happy birthday dear Lionel, happy birthday
to you!
Happy birthday Lionel!
Wow, wow, you guys are throwing a surprise party just for me?
You shouldn't have.
I don't know what to say.
Congratulations, Lionel!
Thank you!
Yeah, congratulations!
Thank you very much!
Who arranged all this?
Oh, it was Laurie's idea!
Heh, I hope you like it!
Yes, Laurie, it's wonderful!
But where's Poke?
Did he forget my birthday again?
This is a party!
Of course he's going to come!
But he said he's going to be a little late, though!
Ah, okay!
So, who wants to have some fun?
Yay!
Thank you. Yes, I'll see into it. Goodbye.
Lionel, what's up with you?
Yes. Yes, you sound like there's something wrong.
Yes, Laurie. Actually, there is.
I've just been informed that my father has passed away last night.
Oh, if there is anything I can do?
No, no, thank you. Thank you. It's all right.
It just took me a bit by surprise. Don't worry.
Lionel, I don't know what to say. I'm so sorry.
Happy birthday to you, happy birthday to you.
Happy birthday, happy birthday to you.
Lionel, you're the man!
One year more and you're still beautiful!
Look, I just stole those flowers for you.
Get up!
Our lorry, what's up with you?
This is his birthday party, not a funeral, you know?
Par-day!
I know this whole concept is new to you, but...
Oh cut it out!
Alright, what's wrong?
Lionel's father is dead.
What do you mean dead?
When did that happen?
And how?
just got a phone call. He passed away in his sleep last night. I am sorry folks, the party is over.
Thank you all for coming, but I think Lionel wants to be alone now.
Bye. Bye. See you guys. So, so, so the old fart has finally hit the bucket. But life goes on.
it's still my birthday and I'd really like to celebrate with you guys and oh
dear I should have kept my mouth shut shouldn't I
Lionel I'm shocked why are you talking about him like that yes you almost sound
like you don't care he's dead no it's not that it's just frankly I don't miss
him that much I haven't heard anything from him since he left more than 10
years ago but his family what's been going on between you and him nothing
that's exactly the problem nothing has been going on he decided to leave me
behind and chase his stupid fantasies instead and I had to find a place to
live for myself and believe me but wasn't easy since it didn't leave me any
money and everything else he owned he sold that's hard to believe yes why did
I don't know. He told me I would understand someday but the day hasn't
come yet and now that he's dead it's probably too late. I could have been the
son of a famous musician but no he preferred digging in the dirt instead.
In the dirt? I'm your session. What was your father's job? He was a singer and a
songwriter and he was doing really well. I swear he was that close to his
breakthrough his songs were playing on all stations he was just about to sign
the big contract and then he quit he decided to become an archaeologist got
that an archaeologist that must have been the single most stupid decision
ever made on earth he threw away a perfect career out of pure selfishness
he didn't care the slightest bit about the consequences I had to face and and
what are you supposed to do now? They want me to come to Cairo to accept my
heritage. For some reason my father insisted that I have to go and pick it
up in person. But I'm not sure I really want to. I mean, what could a guy like him
leave me anyway? A bucket of sand and a shovel? Why Cairo? Because
obviously that was the place where he used to live. He was working for the
museum of forgotten arts whatever that might be I've never heard about this
institution before but it sure sounds like dead no matter what you think of
him you've got to pay your last respect to him you can't just dismiss him like
that this wouldn't make you any better than him and maybe it is worth the
effort I mean they wouldn't make you show up personally if it wasn't important
Yes, we're going to Cairo. We're going to walk like an Egyptian, walk like an Egyptian, walk like an Egyptian.
Hey, hey, hey, wait a minute. Who said we?
I said we. I mean, we ought to stick together, right? And I can't wait to meet the bit, see the lovely beaches, you know, send the like.
Pogue, there is no beach in Cairo.
uh i always wanted to see the museum of forgotten arts oh lori five minutes ago you didn't even know
this museum existed don't you get it we're your friends and we just want to be with you
oh mika that's so sweet all right i guess i don't have another choice then but
guys please keep in mind this is not a vacation we've got serious business to do let's get packing
Walk like an Egyptian, walk like an Egyptian, walk like an Egyptian, walk like an Egyptian.
You sir, art for me?
Yes, the meeting is due. Send in the digital rights managers. At once!
Of course, my producer! Producer!
At your service, almighty producer!
Very well. Gentlemen, I have called you to this special meeting because I'm deeply disappointed.
I have just read the latest sales report. Our profit has increased by 50%, and this is way below the expectations for this quarter.
I find this lack of growth disturbing. How do you expect me to explain this to our shareholders?
My producer, we are still doing a lot of research in this field and it seems people have become strangely inspired lately.
Strangely inspired, you say? That's hard to believe. What do you have to back up your claim?
My numbers indicate that a lot of people are singing unlicensed material under the shower.
And I just received a report of incidences of children in kindergarten being taught public domain nursery songs
officially by their teachers
imagine that's
Disgusting what's next teachers giving away mp3 files in the classroom?
Don't you dare speak the forbidden word?
Which one mp3
E College don't say this again you know what the punishment us yeah my producer
I thought that rule excludes members of the corporation silence what was I about
to say yes it seems that the power of inspiration is on the rise again this
This development has always been my deepest concern.
All sources of inspiration are under our control.
I don't understand how this can be.
Something must have happened.
Perhaps the rumors are true.
But no matter what, we must take action.
Quickly.
Firstly, about the people singing under the shower, call our legal department.
We must exert our influence in establishing new international copyright laws that will
will allow us to demand compensation from the manufacturers of bathroom equipment.
Brilliant idea, my producer.
Then, about the children.
We must increase our presence in schools and kindergartens,
teaching them that singing public songs means depriving hardworking artists
from their God-given right to profit.
We must educate them that licensing is good
and that sharing is evil.
As you command, my producer.
Okay. Now, what are we going to do with you? What are you suggesting in order to redeem yourself?
I beg your forgiveness, my producer. I didn't mean to cause any harm. Please, have mercy. I only said MP that word two times. And, and…
Yes. And?
And I promise, I will never say MP3 again!
Okay, that's enough. Three times. Your behaviour is intolerable. You shall receive your punishment.
No!
What is your verdict, my producer?
The punishment for saying the forbidden word is death by Britney's sphere.
No! No, not that! Please!
What is the issue, my producer?
Britney!
Do we really solve this kind of music?
Yes, we do. And actually, it's quite successful.
God is as empty as Minos Media. Yes, heh heh, Minos Media.
My producer! My producer!
We have tapped into a phone call from the Museum of Forgotten Arts in Egypt.
We finally have the proof that your theory is true.
The document really exists, and the old lion's son is already on his way to claim his heritage.
Hmm, right on cue.
So, Mr. Scruffy Cat Senior really found it.
Remarkable.
And now he's trying to pass it on to his son.
I always knew he couldn't keep a secret to himself.
Too bad for him.
Good for us, though.
Send two of our best men to Cairo and get it before he does.
It's the key to gaining control over all music on this planet.
And we must not miss this opportunity!
Yeah, my producer.
Christopher Scruffycat,
you have tried to cross my plans so many times.
Not this time.
When all this is over, I will be the richest man in the world.
Thank you.
I wouldn't have made it without you.
Tala malaikum.
Welcome to the Museum of Forgotten Arts, my honored friends.
My name is Joseph Alkali. I have been waiting for you.
Alai kum salam!
Hey dude! Um, Alkali, don't...
I mean, aren't you that guy who invented the Energizer Bunny?
I mean, last time I put the batteries in backwards and it kept coming and coming and coming...
Poke! That's not the way to treat a man like him!
Let me show you how it's done.
Alai kum salam, Joseph Alkali!
My name is Lorena MacFook-Manis and my friends and I thank you for your warm welcome.
You are equally welcome. Why don't you and your friends come over and sit down with me?
It's the customs of my people to offer guests a nice cup of Arabian mocha as a gesture of hospitality.
Ah, coffee. Just what I need right now. Give me that.
Uh, Pogue, be careful. This is real Arabian mocha.
Yes, and it's inside the smallest cup I've ever seen.
No challenge for me.
Starbucks is my middle name.
That's the real stuff.
Keeps your heart beating and your pores black.
I never tried this before.
I wouldn't touch it if I were you.
This is not the decaf, fat-free, low-carb dishwater you always sip on.
This is for real men, not for little girls like you.
Hey, calm down, macho man.
We are tough girls.
can handle this and we don't want to be impolite do we Laurie oh I guess no
maybe it's not so bad and that's really nice anybody else wants a mocha all
right I'm sure you're curious why you had to come here in person and what your
father might have left you. The passing of your father has been a great loss to all of us.
He did great things for the museum and found many artifacts that were believed to be lost for
centuries. He devoted his life to scientific research but unfortunately Allah did not bless
him with the success he strived for. I used to be a good friend of him and he asked me to give you
this personal diary and research journal. He told us that it contains all his
knowledge and findings. However, we couldn't make any sense of it. Your
father went a very long way to make sure that it would be handed over to you
personally and that it may never get into the wrong hands. And here it is. He
titled it, finding my way to the temple of Dunovat.
Mm. Mm. Indeed. This doesn't make any sense to me, either. Is this book all he left me?
No. I have two more items for you.
Mm. Let me guess. A bucket of sand and a shovel?
No. He left you two things that were very dear to him. You should cherish them. He never left home without them.
A whip and a hat? Thank you, Daddy.
Daddy, no licensed music in the halls of the museum.
Okay.
Well, what is this museum about anyway?
The exhibits in this museum are the forgotten songs
of the old ages.
There was a time when music was not produced by producers
and consumed by consumers.
Music was in the art of everyone.
People would come together and sing and dance
and share their songs.
Music was a part of our everyday lives,
and there used to be songs for every occasion.
Those must have been wonderful times.
Nowadays, songs have become intellectual property,
turning open hearts into greedy minds.
And what has once been an inspiration for everyone
has now become a means to fill the pockets of just a few.
This museum preserves what is left
of the songs of the old ages.
Oh, can we hear one of them?
Sure, follow me.
Beautiful melody.
I've never heard that melody before.
See, that's why we are preserving them.
There is a wealth of all songs that are very beautiful but nobody knows about anymore today.
Really?
And each of these boxes holds one of the forgotten songs?
Oh, this is so exciting. I can't wait to hear all of them. What's inside this one?
No, no, don't touch that one. No!
This box again. This is our collection of spare vocals. We need them for respiration purposes.
Sometimes we find songs that are not in good shape and then we use these for replacement.
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
May I open this one?
Sure.
Wait a minute. That's just a box with a light in it.
Oh, my mistake. As you can see there is no way to make big money with all this old stuff.
stuff. And exactly that is the reason why we are a thorn in the side of the
international media corporations. We are under their strict supervision. One wrong
note and this place will be swarming with Armenians.
H verh
h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h h
They are coming
This is the THX. Soundcheck!
You are totally surrounded!
Open the door!
And there you are!
You've got something that belongs to us!
You've got the choice.
Hand over the diary, or...
certain death!
You've got 5 seconds!
Uh, the diary?
Fiery? Well, here, take it, I don't need it.
No, no!
No, don't you dare come any closer! You shall not have it!
But, but, Mika...
No, no, Lionel, you can't give it to them.
We went all the way to Egypt to get this book.
And five minutes later, the Thought Police turns up and wants to take it away?
Don't you smell anything fishy?
All right, you've had your chance. Now prepare to die.
Attack!
I want to take-
Run!
No Mika, Mika it's not worth it!
Oh stop talking!
Just run!
Run everybody!
I have seen this coming!
Follow me!
I know a secret way out of here!
There we are.
We've been walking for hours.
Never seen the light of another day.
Eh, day?
You're midnight sweetie pie, it's full moon!
Just creeping out of the graves, just working for hymns walking by.
Yeah, the full moon always makes me horny too.
Why is it that your innocent guys always got the good stuff?
I wanna be a victim too.
Laurie, when will you finally grow up?
Vampires and werewolves and all the other unthinkable creatures are just a figment of your imagination.
They don't exist, just like Santa Claus or the Easter Bunny.
Laurie you you still believe in I don't know what to admit it you really thought
I still believe in Santa Claus didn't you yeah yeah you really got me there I
must admit I wouldn't have been surprised if it had been true see I'm
more grown up than you think as Mika said we are tough girls we can handle
this right mika uh mika mika is gone where is she where is she she got eaten by the werewolves
lion now oh there you are lorry what are you talking about i am sorry it took me so long
but i had to get the thx police guys acquainted with the three tenors before i could join you
Oh, I'm so glad you made it we were worried about you
Ah, no need to worry having the black belt and cat fighting must be good for something
Thank you so much. We wouldn't have made it without your help. Ah, don't mention it
Come on get a grip
Lori calm down, please
pushed around and never taken seriously. And nobody seems to care at all, but I have to say, when it comes to-
Larry!
When it comes to-
Ahh!
Thank you, Polk.
What's about time?
I think we'll be safe here for a while. This graveyard is not known to the common people.
Lionel, do you still have the diary?
Because now I am really curious about your father's notes.
If there are so many people trying so hard to get it, and your father making such a fuss
about its secrecy, it must be very very important.
Alright.
Alright then.
I would suggest we go through it together, line by line.
Okay.
So it's titled, Finding my way to the Temple of Duno-Watt.
Whatever the temple of Dunnewat might be, it seems to be a place of utmost importance
and this book is probably the key to finding it.
This is what it says on the first page.
The politician's daughter was accused of drinking water.
No tea or tomato juice, you'll see no potato juice.
What?
Well, wait, wait, let me continue reading.
Coffee ketchup and soda?
What's that about the beer?
Well done.
Even excellent savour.
Coffee ketchup gives them flavour.
This is just bullshit.
Then it goes on like this.
This is the rock that rolls.
I'm not moving too fast or too slow.
If this is the rock that rolls,
as soon as it hits you, you'll know.
Well, that's even worse.
Yes, we were equally confused when we got to that part.
Okay, okay.
Ugh, Laurie.
What's the matter?
Laurie, forget it.
If you refuse to calm down, that muscle will stay on.
Now stop whining and let us do our work.
Okay?
Okay.
All the happy saints go marching in, and if one of those saints steps out of line, he'll
have to start again.
I don't know what your dad has been smoking, but I want some of that shit.
Because Jacob's golden ladder gets slippery at the top, and many a happy-go-lucky saint
has made that long, long drop.
I really wonder what this is all about.
Yeah, me too.
It's really strange here.
Laurie, one last time, stay put.
There are no monsters, there are no vampires, werewolves or zombies, okay?
And we have serious business to do here.
you understand oh I have no idea what has gotten into her maybe it's the full
moon now but nobody ever got into her anyway okay let's continue a giant
vision in the distance chase that rainbow down the tree speak
to me and I listen to them carefully whether standing still or blowing in the wind I hear them
singing the trees speak they whispered a sweet melody the keepers of more wisdom than you and I
so listen to them carefully all right okay we have read through the first four pages and you know
what I didn't understand a single word Lionel are you sure your dad still had his wits together
I'm not so sure anymore.
Hey guys, you noticed anything?
No, what do you mean?
Laurie has stopped whining.
Hey, now that you mention it.
Oh, what about time?
So...
You can be quiet after all.
See, it wasn't that hard, was it?
Come on, let me remove this.
Come on.
Okay guys, we have no choice.
We'll have to go through it again.
Let's see if there's something we've been missing.
There must be a meaning to this.
You know, the reasons of my father
might be hard to understand,
but I'm quite sure he wasn't crazy.
This must be some kind of code.
The politician's daughter was accused of drinking water.
Hey, I know that line.
Really?
What?
Yes, I tried to tell you guys, but you wouldn't let me.
Okay.
Well, you know, Laurie, it does sound vaguely familiar to me, but I can't really remember
when I first heard it.
So where is it from?
It's an old song, done by Frank Sinatra.
It's the coffee song.
And it goes like this.
You can't get chorizo to...
We in Brazil made a juice.
They've got a lot of juice.
Aren't you made of juice?
You'll see.
Coffee pickles.
We are chill.
Brazil!
Well done, Laurie.
the first part of the puzzle oh did i okay so we have to go to brazil but brazil is a big country
we need to figure out where exactly we need to go does anybody know the names of the most important
cities in brazil sure there are brazilia sau palo rio de janeiro manaus nodal salvador sau felix
Stop, stop, stop. What was the last one again?
São Félix?
São Félix loosely translates to the lucky saint.
Look at this line in the book.
And many a happy-go-lucky saint has made that long, long drop.
Well, I must say, not bad.
So we need to go to São Félix in Brazil.
São Félix, a nice old town at the edge of the Brazilian rainforest.
And what do the other lines mean?
I hear a pound pound pounding in my chest this is the rock that rolls as
soon as it hits you you know the trees speak to me so I listen to them
carefully I don't have a clue Laurie but we finally have a starting point I hope
those lines will make more sense once we get there please accept the advice of an
experienced archaeologist try to memorize those lines you might get
separated or lose the book. So it's decided we are going to visit the
Brazilian rainforest. Ah Brazil, it is such a wonderful place of ancient
history and adventure. I wish I could come with you. Well if you want to we can
use all help we get. Yes, why don't you join us? Oh thanks for the offer but I
really can't go with you. I'm an old man myself and if I don't stay here and take
care of the museum will yes my little one it's time to say goodbye but before
you leave I've got something for you oh what is it what is it here please
accept this flask of real Arabian mocha as my farewell gift oh thank you very
much hey cool oh you won that's the good stuff
thank you yourself that's very kind of you but we must go now to the Brazilian
rainforest but how do we get there just follow me I know a secret passage to the
airport why I am not surprised something is happening I don't know what it is I
can feel it my urge to break free is stronger than ever before I'm feeling
restless. Pacing back and forth in my confinement like an animal in its cage. I wish I could
see more clearly. It feels like someone is coming. Could it be possible that the key
has not been lost, but merely misplaced? I can feel darkness, but there is also light.
Are they coming to free me, or are they coming to kill me? Let them come. I may be old, but
I'm not rusty. Be it songs of war or songs of love, just let me sing.
This is me!
I spent my last three bucks on the license to put it onto my playlist.
However, the license to remove it from the playlist will be another five bucks.
But I'm broke!
Alright, alright. For the good of society, everyone look into your pockets.
Does anyone have any spare change so we can make this stop?
Okay, here we go.
The door dropped.
What?
It's ready to jump?
Hey, did you really believe those traps were safety belts?
Well, in a way they are.
And don't you remember the line from that book?
And many a happy-go-lucky saint has made that long, long drop.
The management of Polk Airlines wishes you a pleasant flight.
Two, three and hold.
Okay guys, are you ready? Mika? Po?
Ready! Let's rock!
Sweet! Of the entire goddamn rainforest! And I step into it at once!
Great! This is just great! A new world record!
I chipped 8 claws, deranged my hairdo, ripped my claws apart and dislocated one shoulder in less than 10 seconds!
But two on the top ten worst things that have ever happened to me.
Right after number one, being hit over the head with a tombstone.
Can somebody please cut off this thing?
I want to cry now, having been kicked out of a plane, crashing into the Brazilian rainforest,
and landing inside of this dark cave that has obviously no other exit than a skylight I fell through,
which I can't reach from down here.
But it can't possibly get any worse than this.
This is so depressing.
A thousand years of waiting for the next adventurers coming into my cave to be crushed by me.
And now they don't even run away from me anymore.
This is so depressing.
You are not going to crush me?
Oh, I can still do it if you want to.
Although it's not much fun if you don't run away.
Hold still, I'll make it quick.
No, no, no, no, I just changed my mind, thank you very much.
What's your name?
Does it matter?
To me? Yes, it does.
I used to have a name, but I'm too depressed to remember.
Ah, what makes you so depressed?
Well, are you happy to be down here?
Oh, no, why?
See what I mean?
They put me in this cave and told me, watch over this glowing stone, if anyone wants to
touch it, crush them.
They made me believe that it's an incredible honorable task and that I'll be richly rewarded
some day.
And then they said goodbye and made the entrance of the cave collapse.
I feel sooooo stupid.
Have you never tried breaking through the barrier of the cave entrance?
I tried that once.
The only thing that happened was a loud crunch, and when I regained my senses I found out
that several smaller parts had crumbled off me.
Ouch.
That must have hurt badly.
It did hurt.
But it's not the worst thing.
Not?
What happened?
Baba!
Adventures with Dabra couldn't be the third of September
Today, I have a chance to make a loss
Will I try to break free?
Depending on you, to help me get out
But no, instead they keep singing
Adventures
The only song they know
And they've been singing it every day for thousands of years
Man, I'm sooo depressed
I'm going to crush you now
No, wait, wait, wait, wait.
You remind me of something I read in a book.
This is the rock that rolls, not moving too fast or too slow.
This is the rock that rolls, as soon as it hits you, you know.
They wrote a book about me?
Yes, it's the journal of the world-renowned...
...stonyologist, Dr. Christopher Scruffycat.
You know what? You're famous. That's where I know you from.
Oh great. So now I'm famous. But what's good to me if I can't even leave this place? Thank you. Now I'm even more depressed than ever before.
But you can leave this place. All you have to do is slam through the barrier.
I already tried and I failed.
Hey, let me tell you something.
Don't let your failures define who you are.
You're only a failure if you fail to try.
But I tried!
Then try again!
You're a strong piece of rock, and you're made to roll.
Hm...
Do you really think so?
Sure, I must know I read the book.
You're the mightiest rock in the world.
Come on, tell me you can do it.
Hm...
Can I?
Come on, I know you can do it. Give me an R.
R?
Give me an O.
O.
Give me a C.
C.
Give me a K.
K.
O.
I am the rock.
S.
Nobody can stop you. Go.
Let's roll.
Powers of positive thinking.
There's some truth in the saying being dumped like a rock.
I'm free! It's wonderful! The flowers are blooming and the birds are singing and... and...
Oh, I landed on a slope! The tree! Incoming! Sorry! Oh, no! Be careful, old lady!
So this is the little glowing thing the rock was supposed to protect. I wonder what it might be good for.
It means sounds it makes. Better I take it with me. You never know.
Pressure! Pressure!
Three! Nothing's happening!
No, Lionel! Pull it again!
It won't open!
Lionel? Lionel? Can you hear me? Can you hear me?
Oh, wake up, Lionel! You must wake up!
Oh, Lionel, please! You must not die!
Not here! Not now! Lion, no!
Hello? Where am I? Is anybody here? Am I dead?
Like it down here. Are you comfortable?
Because now it's time to think, Lionel.
Why did you go to Egypt? Was it because you cared about your father's wishes?
Or was it just because you hoped your heritage would contain more than just a dusty book?
Were you hoping for money, gold, treasures?
Would you have traveled all the way if you had known what your heritage was?
Come on, you can admit it now that it's over.
Was it worth having one of your best friends kicked out of an airplane at five thousand feet?
Really?
Think!
But...
But I was... I was just...
Well...
Let me explain, please...
Please...
Poke?
This crashed through the trees, marvelous!
Your father would have been proud of you.
If you had survived, that is.
Hey, come on!
Now that it's over, nothing matters anymore.
Let's get drunk! I'd like to bring out a toast to the marvelous Lance Gruffyke,
getting himself killed while foolishly attempting to make up for the failures of a lifetime and less than a week. Cheers!
Poke, Poke! No, it's not true! No, at least it's only partly true.
poke why does nobody listen to me dad is that you you're alive you didn't care
for the last ten years so why would you care now no I please listen to me we
don't have much time you are my son and for me you have always been the most
precious thing in the world leaving you alone like this was the hardest decision
I have a head to make but things were at stake that was so important not just for you
But for the entire world that I had no other choice
Please you must trust me. It sounds me to see that you have stopped believing in me, but it's not too late
You must fulfill my legacy or otherwise the world may be changed forever
Trust me Lionel because I am your father. I am proud of you Lionel. I always was I
I love you.
No! Dad! Come back! Don't leave me! Don't leave me again!
There is so much I need to tell you, which I never did, even if I should have.
Dad! Please!
Oh Lionel! Now you see where you got yourself with logic.
If only once you had followed your heart.
Now you put not only yourself, but all of your friends in danger.
And why?
Because you're a coward.
The only reason why you never talked to your father was
because you were afraid to confront yourself with him.
What are you?
A big strong lion?
I will tell you what you are.
You're a sheep.
Berlionel.
I bet when you were at school, you were beaten up by the girls.
Na na na na na na.
Ouch!
That hurt!
Oh, now, come on!
Do you dare hitting me back?
Oh, come on!
You don't dare hitting me?
Lionel is a coward!
Ah, Mika, no!
Stop hitting me, please!
Oh, you're just getting what you deserve, Lionel!
Sometimes the truth does hurt!
Oh, come on!
Fight! Fight!
You coward! Finally learn how to fight!
Nobody messes with Mika!
No, no, no! I don't want to! No, please! No!
Ouch! No, don't hit me, please!
Lionel! Lionel!
Wake up! Please! Oh, come on, Lionel!
You must not die! Lionel!
We've come this far!
You can't leave me now. Don't leave me.
Oh no, this can't be true.
Oh Lionel, I can't live without you.
And there is so much I wanted to tell you, but I never dared.
Oh please, I never had the chance to say how much I love you.
What am I going to do now?
Oh, this is so terrible.
Lionel! Lionel, you're alive!
No, don't hit me. Please, don't hit me.
Are you alright? I thought I had lost you forever.
My head hurts like hell and I'm feeling kind of dizzy.
I'm so glad you're alive.
So am I. But what happened?
Your parachute didn't open. But the tree stopped your fall.
I must have been really lucky. No broken bones, I think.
Oh, Mika. Mika, I'm feeling so miserable about how I treated my father.
Oh, come on, Lionel. Don't be so hard on yourself.
You are paying your final respect to him after all.
And you even risked your life for it. What more could a father ask for?
for no Mika you don't understand my father is dead nothing I do today can
make up for the things I didn't do for the last ten years
don't you realize Mika I was the only one thinking about himself all the time
even coming here was just because of my curiosity and I even put me and my best
friends in danger look at me the same could have happened to you or poke or as
possibly happened to Laurie. I don't even see them around here. Where are they? They could be dead
and it's all my fault. Hush, Lionel. Hush, calm down. It's all right. Don't be so hard on yourself.
We are your friends. You didn't force us to come with you, remember? Yeah, yes, you're right.
there there you're alive and I am alive too and I am sure the others are doing
fine as well oh come on don't cry it's alright Oh Mika Mika I'm so glad that
you're here and I'm glad that you are here Mika what shall I do what shall we
do we've crashed into the middle of the jungle and now I'm all confused until
now i always thought i knew what i should do but this time i don't have any clue at all
i'm so clueless what should i do stop hitting my trunk with your head for a start
who's talking the one who saved your life uh talking tree excellent observation mr homes
And don't even think of thanking me for saving your life by sacrificing at least two branches,
a dozen twigs and countless leaves.
This will take years to grow back.
A talking tree!
Lioner, remember the line from the book?
The trees speak to me, so I listen to them carefully.
And we must be on the right track.
Hey, hey tree, do you have a name?
And thanks for saving my life.
You can call me Mr. Tree, and you're welcome.
All right then, Mr. Tree, it seems that we need your help one more time.
We are looking for something, but we don't know exactly what it is.
It might be a map, a hint, an artifact, or something else.
It was mentioned in a book, referring to a talking tree, like you.
Do you know anything that might be of help?
Oh, yes.
How do you know?
In fact, I am the guardian of a very mighty artifact.
It was given to me more than a thousand years ago.
Oh, what is it?
I can't tell you, unless you can prove
that you're the ones destined to receive it.
And how are we supposed to do that?
Well, if you are the ones, you are supposed to know.
Shit, that means we are stuck.
Lionel, do you still have the diary?
Uhh, no.
I must have lost it crashing into our friend, Mr. Tree.
Oh, hey!
I concentrate like this!
Will you the heck stop sawing?
We are trying to hold a-
Hey you, are you crazy?
What are you doing here?
I just wanted you to ask the same thing.
Came to see I'm clearing the rainforest.
Clearing the-
Jumping down trees, cutting wood, trimming the vegetation, you know.
know and that one is next number 696 come on people get out of the way this
is dangerous oh no you can't do this stop please put that thing down all
right who sent you here Greenpeace Robinwood World Wildlife Fund United
Treehackers of Oklahoma City the concerned parents of Minnesota what are
you talking about we are from the Museum of Forgotten Arts in Cairo can't you
Did you just cut down a different tree than this one?
Well, there are lots of trees in the rainforest.
Big ones, small ones, old ones, young ones, and more leaves on the glass leaves, so...
For the highest wood quality, we have to be a tad more specific, you know?
Ouch.
But you can't do that!
He is our friend!
He saved my life!
Uh, what the...
Whatever. I've had enough. Out of my way.
No!
no you're not getting near this tree Mika I've learned something there are
times where logic will not get you anywhere we can give this man this guy
here as many explanations as we want he will not going to understand now listen
panda you can't chop down this tree because I have to fulfill my father's
legacy I have denied my father long enough but I tell you I Lionel C
Scruffycat am proud to be the son of Christopher Scruffycat may he rest in
peace and I am defending this tree in the name of my father and if you want to
take it down you'll have to talk me down first what you're the son of
Christopher Scruffycat the Christopher Scruffycat the singer you knew him well
not in person but when I was young I was a huge fan I still own all his CDs he's
childhood memory always wonder what happened to him okay okay okay then listen my father passed
away 40 days ago and i'm here to fulfill his last wish i can't explain it to you but this tree here
is a part of it i can't let you kill it wow you're going through all that trouble just for your
father's last will pretty impressive you must have held a hell of a respect for your father
Oh well I do what I can you know I'd read it off to spare this tree but I
have to follow my order so I lose my job wait what number did this tree have
again six nine six let's have a look this must be a mix-up this tree has the
number nine six nine and nine six nine is not on my list cuz silly me I nearly
got down the wrong tree uh you mean oh i see thank you oh sorry for the
misunderstanding have a nice day bye that was close yes it was
okay this time you saved my life thank you
now i really owe you one what can i do for you
Well, you said you were guarding a certain artifact?
All right, you shall have it. Nobody wanted it for ages, so why shouldn't I give it to you?
What on earth is that?
It's a secret artifact. The thing about secrets is that nobody's supposed to know about them.
It was handed to me by some sort of high priest and he simply didn't tell me what it is.
So, I can't tell you. I'm sorry.
We will find out eventually, but first we'll have to find the rest of our party.
I bid you farewell then, and thank you again for saving my life.
I consider you good friends. I hope you will return someday.
Goodbye, Mr. Tree.
Goodbye. Come on, Mika, let's go.
Hey, hey, that's for me!
Oh, wait.
Lori?
Lori!
Mika?
Lionel!
Mika!
Oh, Lionel!
Oh, tree!
Poke!
What are you doing up there?
Oh, wow.
Now, out to a tree bondage.
What do you think I'm doing? I've been fucking hanging this fucking tree for three fucking hours.
And it's fucking beginning to get to my fucking nerves.
I can see your balls.
How do you fucking morons get me the fuck out of this fucking tree so I can calm down and kick your fucking asses?
Oh, I'd sure like to. But how are we supposed to do that, huh?
I don't care, just get me down!
All right, all right, we've got to make a plan.
How do we get him down?
Preferably without getting our asses kicked.
Got that poke!
Can't we just leave him up there?
My day has been bad enough already.
No!
Okay.
How about throwing coconuts at him until he falls down?
No way!
hmm okay then we could rip this tree with dynamite and boom instant untangling
no oh well if you don't like my suggestions I can just as well shut up
who's going to listen to me anyway.
Nori don't start it again I'm completely finished with my nerves and this is the last thing I need now you really should
Shh! Did you hear something? I think someone's coming.
That was a good one.
Okay, it was just bulk. Where were we?
Well, this completely threw me off. I think I was about to say...
Freeze! This is the THX!
Look who we have here. You are under arrest.
don't even think of moving our L this is really annoying mr. Lionel's
graphical no matter what we try you just refuse to die I have no idea how you
made it your parachute was never sent to open well indeed it didn't you seem to
be a really tough guy but there will be no longer have helped to you because now
you're coming with us oh you you try to kill Lionel you bastards oh come here I
will slit your chest open and drink your blood while your hearts are still beating I will kill you I will kill you
felines are so easy to overcome just grab them by the scruff of their neck
and their caring reflexes will kick in.
Now, isn't she cute?
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
How on earth did you manage to follow us without a copy of the diary?
Well, that's easy.
It's true, you did have the only copy of that book,
but here's a little hint for your next adventure.
If you browse through secret documents,
you should rather not do that directly underneath the surveillance cup.
Do.
Okay, enough talking.
Ladies and gentlemen, your vacation ends here.
I don't know what the producer has in mind for you,
but it surely won't be pretty.
Now go.
I said go.
You... marry Ken!
Shut up!
Go!
I'm still up here!
Hey! Come back!
it's always the same hey you assholes if you don't want me to be with you why don't you just tell me
we are all grown-up people aren't we hey come on give me a chance i bet i can be a good person
i do ah shit i gotta get down here by myself then i give up i'm completely tailed in this fucking
parachute. Shit! I'm stuck! Lionel! Mika! Come back and get me down! Lionel? Mika?
Larry? How am I ever supposed to get down this fucking tree?
I thought Larry was a bad driver. Oh well at least I'm on the ground again. I mean I
i like bondage but this is ridiculous
okay now what these trees look all the same should it go this way or that way
oh what about the way back come on poke time to think you must think a way to out of here think
come on think think oh my stuff snapped the muscle in my brain man that hurts
I guess I'll just lay down here and think a little bit more carefully.
Think.
Booger, booger, booger, booger, booger, booger, booger, booger, booger.
How am I supposed to think with all the zugabuger stuff going on?
so hey stop complaining we're doing an important job does it look like we were
running about just for fun who are you anyway hey that's funny I just wanted to
ask you the same thing we are the honorable carriers of the sacred chest
of the old ages and who are you I'm you're a poke I've never heard of a poke
what's a poke I am poke I am the dick in ridiculous you are the what in the what
I forget about it so you're the fucking carousel for fucking something so what
the heck are you doing we are carrying the sacred chest of the old ages isn't
that obvious okay I can I can see that but what for why are you running around
all the time hmm could it be to make sure that nobody gets their chest okay
wouldn't it be easier to simply guard the chest I mean without moving no well
they're fully shiny yeah everybody knows gods can be overwhelmed well then what
about looking it locking it away and a crypto or in a fault or something now
that would be an even more foolish idea everybody knows locks can be broken well
I assure you still got all marbles you know listen we've been doing this since
for 2,000 years do you really think we never thought about all this okay I'll
explain it to you please let's pretend we made all the effort of putting up
guards and walls and logs and traps and stuff this takes ages and now some
adventurers comes along tricks the guards breaks the locks and defeats the
traps and in the end only option you are left with is grabbing the artifact and
run away as fast as you can now if running away is your only option what
was the point in setting up all these barriers in the first place yes so the
The High Council of Ooga Booga has decided to save our energy for the really important matters.
We skipped the all effort and just started running art from the start.
And we've proudly been doing so for 2000 years.
It's the most efficient way to protect the artefact. End of discussion.
Ooga Booga Ooga Booga Ooga Booga Ooga
Okay. And what's inside this chest that makes it worth running to and fro for like 2000 years?
And what's that pounding noise?
We don't know exactly. All we do know is that it must be a very mighty artifact.
And, well, that it's obviously making very strange noises.
The high priest gave it to us to make sure that only the chosen ones may get hold of it.
And what's your job in this affair?
I am the apprentice of the honourable chest carriers. Once I'll be grown up, I'm going to be a chest carrier, too.
But before I can become one, I'll have to complete a highly sophisticated and challenging two-year training program.
And what kind of highly sophisticated training is that? What do you have to do?
Well, I've got to run after them and bring them water when they're thirsty.
That's all? That's Yugabuga University?
Hey wait, this is not as easy as it seems. Being a chest carrier requires highly trained skills.
It's very hard to run at precisely the right speed, you know.
If you go too slow, someone could catch up with you and steal the artifact.
Yes, and running too fast will make you pass out.
Well, no, that's actually not the problem.
The catch is, you've got to stay below the speed limit.
What? There's a speed limit? I mean, in the jungle?
Aye, think about it. This is the Brazilian rainforest.
If everyone was allowed to go as fast as they wanted, there wouldn't be a single tree left.
Uh-oh. There goes another one.
One day, I'll be one of the honorable chest-carriers, running through the forest, swiftly like the wind, listening to the birds and the pounding in my chest.
Always remember the lines from the book. I hear a pound, pound, pounding in my chest, pounding in my chest, pounding in my chest.
wait wait wait wait a minute that sound coming from that box I mean how shall I
say I think I need that artifact yeah sure but only the ode to the chosen ones
may approach the chest and how can you tell if someone is the chosen one we
don't know we're supposed to recognize them when they come here I am I must get
the chest but you can't you don't look like a chosen one okay so let's pretend
I'm not the chosen one would there be any other way to get the artifact maybe
maybe not come on you can tell me everything will be cool I can keep a
secret well I probably could tell you if there was a way to get the artifact but
There is no such thing as a free lunch, if you know what I mean.
Okay, but what do I have to do?
The carriers are thirsty and it's my duty to bring them water.
But I'm feeling pretty exhausted, you know, and I thought maybe you could give me a hand.
All you've got to do is to take this bottle of water and run after them so they can have something to drink.
all right and then you tell me if
there is a way for me to get hold of the
artifact. well fair enough and that
sounds easy
give me that bottle
ooga- ooga- ooga- ooga- ooga
anyway guys guys! i have water for you
i said wait!
CS particles
it was more exhausting than being the
guest of honor on a rabbit springer party I told you it's hotter than it
looks okay I can read the water for you now you
must tell me if there is a way for me to get hold of the artifact yes you're
right now I can tell you there is no way to get hold of the artifact what but you
promise yes I promise to tell you if there is a way and there's no way I told
you just like I promised what and I just found something out about you you are
precisely as damp as you look thanks for doing my work ferret what maybe I look
them but you can't imagine how you're gonna look after I broke your nose I was
I was fast enough to catch up with your Uga Boogals, and I was certainly fast enough to catch up with you too.
Well, catch me if you can.
Huh?
Meep meep!
Hey!
When I catch you, I'll seek a bloody how to fuck up your goddamn arms!
Ahh!
What was that?
A speed trap?
In the middle of the jungle?
What the fuck?
I think I'm blind.
Uga la boogala bo.
Um, who?
Me?
How much? You guys must be joking.
I don't have any money. I just fell out of a plane.
And I don't have anything except for like a bottle of Arabian mocha.
So now what?
I get it. You guys want my parachute.
Okay. Let me just fetch it for you.
you that's pretty messed up but yes here it is if it makes you happy have fun
with the parachute I can't believe that this little sucker escaped if I ever meet
that guy again this is getting worse and worse oh well at least I was lucky they
I took my parachute and I bought precious coffee.
There's an awful lot of coffee in Brazil.
It's over, but hey, I got an idea.
Now I know how to get to the chest.
I hope for those guys that I look much dumber than I really am.
Hello? Hello? Are you thirsty again? I got something for you.
Oh
birds chirping
Ooga Booga Booga Booga!
Omgaonga?
Booga Booga Booga!
oha?
Oogah Booga Boogah
Ooga Booga
Is everybody done?
Let's see what we have here.
So...
Whoa!
Shiny thing!
This is what we've been looking for.
It's round and flashy and shiny.
And...
And it's beautiful.
And it's mine!
Nobody shall have it.
It's mine!
Mine alone!
My motherfucking precious!
I must not let them have it!
Heh heh heh heh heh heh heh heh
Whoa!
Wow. Caffeine flashback.
Alright, Lionel. Here I come.
Never underestimate the power of Arabian mocha.
Poke wins, carry a lust. Yay!
That's the way, uh huh, uh huh, I like it, uh huh, uh huh
Oh, shit!
I don't understand.
Why don't they open the gates?
I feel they have the key, but don't they know how to open the gates?
Has the key fallen into the wrong hands?
Or has the knowledge of the ritual been lost?
Am I doomed to stay here forever?
I can feel the darkness growing stronger.
I must do something, but my hands are bound.
This place is like a golden cage.
While it protects me from all that is dark,
It bars me from fighting the darkness outside
Gods, please. Let them remember how to use the key. Let them remember the ancient words to set me
Shut up
The mighty producers on his way. He wants to talk to you
You'll live at least as long as it takes for him to arrive. So
Enjoy your lives while they last
Who the heck is the producer? And what makes him mighty?
Oh, you naive little thing. Don't you know what a producer is?
Who do you think writes all the high-scoring, top-ten chart breakers?
The musicians themselves?
Those are just puppets, barely intelligent enough to hold a microphone.
The producer is the one who draws the strings, making them dance.
Without the producer, there would be no music.
Yep, no music at all.
But that's complete bullshit.
Every talented person can write music.
I must know. My father was both a singer and a songwriter.
You don't expect me to believe that, do you?
I know that is completely impossible.
No producer, no music.
Now, silence. There he comes.
Ladies and gentlemen, the producer.
Your service, almighty producer!
Lionel Christopher Scruffycap.
So we meet at last.
I must say, you have a striking similarity to your father.
You knew my father?
Yes, I did.
I wasn't always a producer, you know.
Many, many years ago, your father and I used to be good friends.
He was an aspiring musician and I used to be a talent scout for the record company that was publishing him.
At first, everything worked out fine. Your father was a pretty successful musician.
Later, when I eventually got promoted, they gave me the chance to name a successor.
And I thought, your father might be a good choice.
So, he got the offer and gladly accepted it.
But... but then, what happened then?
Well, it seems your father had a few misconceptions about the duties of a talent scout.
You know, many people think that record companies send out talent scouts
in order to search for talented people in the hope of discovering the stars of tomorrow.
But when your father was clued in on the real mission he was supposed to fulfill,
Or should I say, he suddenly began losing his enthusiasm.
Or in other words, he threw his career.
What was so horrible about his new job that he absolutely couldn't tolerate?
There is a secret that is well kept from people outside the corporation.
I'm not supposed to tell you either, but you're not going to live to tell anybody.
The inspiration behind all music does not come out of thin air.
They are actual, physical sources of inspiration.
From them, inspiration used to flow freely,
equally enlightening all the people across the lands.
Now, seen from a business perspective,
this is not exactly the ideal.
How are you supposed to sell something
which is a resource free for all, like the air you breathe?
That's where our talent scouts come in.
They used to be the ones searching
and finding these sources of inspiration
and bringing them under our control.
Your father was horrified by the very idea.
He didn't like the concept of running short inspiration
to artificially increase the value of our products.
I can relate to that.
At one time, we thought we had all sources of inspiration
under our control.
Talon scouts were no longer needed.
However, your father believed that there was one more
source of inspiration that we had failed to discover.
He was determined to find it and make sure
that we would never gain control over it.
At first, we didn't pay much attention to him.
We thought he was just a ranting, disgruntled ex-employee.
However, we were smart enough
to keep his research activities under close supervision.
He knew that, of course.
He never let anything slip, until now.
In a way, I have to thank you.
Without you, I would never have been able to decode the riddles in your father's journal.
Now we know that there is indeed one last source of inspiration, hidden within the walls of the long-forgotten Temple of Danowat.
And in just a few hours, it will be mine!
You! You are such a piece of...
I am speechless!
And what's going to happen with us now?
You know, I really hate to get my paws dirty. I think I'll just leave you here.
And soon, nothing will be left of you but a bunch of nameless, rotting skeletons in the middle of the Brazilian rainforest.
And nobody will ever find you.
You must go now and prepare the ceremony.
Have a nice death.
Oh, come back, you coward! You slimy, rotten scoundrel!
Come back and fight like a-
Mika, Mika, Mika, stop.
You know this is not going to get you anywhere.
And remember, there is still hope.
Poke is still out there.
Oh, you're honestly putting your face in Poke?
I don't know.
I think the only thing Poke would be capable of is making things considerably worse.
Think of it.
Following our tracks and showing up here would be about the most stupid thing he possibly could do.
Because when he comes here...
Ta-da!
Book to the rescue! Time to surrender! You have no chance!
I got the green belt and take one leap!
Who? Who? Who?
Boot to the head.
Ouch!
What the hell is this?
Yes! Yes!
Do you know this guy?
This must have been the most stupid rescue attempt I've ever witnessed!
Oh, Pogue, you idiot! You ruined everything!
You've been our last hope!
Oh, right. You wanted to meet your friends?
No problem. There's enough space in the cage for all of you.
Yup, lots of space.
Hey, let me go! I'm not an idiot!
than it yet. Yes you are. No I'm not! At least not compared to these two boneheads.
Hey buddy, you obviously don't know what you're saying. We are captains of the mighty
producers personal guard. We are members of the international elite. Yup, elite. I believe
it when I see it. I'm much smarter than you are and I can prove it. Come on, challenge
Give me a parcel or something.
Hey, do you know the riddle with the shepherd, the sheep, the cabbage, and the wolf?
No, never heard of it.
Oh, very good. I mean, may I explain it to you?
Fire away?
Well, there is a man with a boat who must move a wolf, a sheep, and a box of cabbage to the other side of the river.
there is a catch the boat is very small so the poor guy can on always only take
one thing with him and now his problem is that when he leaves the wolf and the
sheep alone the wolf will eat the sheep when he leaves the sheep and the cabbage
alone the sheep will eat the cabbage so what does he have to do in order to get
all three things safely to the other side oh ha that's easy that's easy okay
Okay, ferret guy, you're toast.
Yup, toast.
Alright, then let the contest begin.
Poke, the ferret starts.
Alright, he's not going to solve it anyway.
Okie dokie, let's see.
Just a second.
Alright, let's see.
First he moves the cabbage to the other side.
And then...
No wait, then the sheep will be fucked.
Darn! So then he has to move the wolf first.
Oh, come on, come on, you're so stupid. If you move the wolf first, he will leave the sheep and the cabbage behind.
And the sheep will eat the cabbage. Don't you get it?
No, no, no, no. Wait, wait. I just need a little visualization.
Huh?
So let's pretend that you're the sheep and you're the wolf.
Yup, the wolf.
And I am the cabbage.
okay now what okay let's pretend this bridge is the river of course the first
thing you have to do is taken the sheep over to the other side watch me I'm the
sheep then the Shepherd gets the wolf over the river that's you yeah that's me
And now, and now, uh, the shepherd sends the sheep back over the river, because the wolf is here.
Wait, wait, wait. This didn't get us anywhere, did it?
And besides, it's my turn. You messed it up and now I have to start all over again.
Now, let's pretend you are the cabbage.
And I'm the shepherd. Now I, the shepherd, take you, the cabbage, over the river. And now I'll go back to pick up the sheep.
There is no sheep. You forgot to say who's the sheep.
What? Ah, shit! Okay, give me one final chance, all right?
Okay, but this will be really the last chance, buddy.
Again, I make sure not to forget anybody this time. I'm the shepherd, Mika is the cabbage, Lionel is the wolf and Laurie is the sheep.
Of course.
Hey!
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, now I got it!
Now I got it!
Hey!
It's still my turn!
Ah, Po, come on, don't be a spoilsport.
If he wants to solve it, why don't you let him?
Well, I have to.
Go ahead.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Step one.
The shepherd takes the sheep over the river.
All right, I'm the shepherd, I'll do everything you say.
So step two, the shepherd goes back and takes the cabbage over the river.
Okay, your wish is my command.
So now, now comes the trick.
Step three, he takes the sheep back with him so he won't eat the cabbage.
Hey smart move, you're good.
Keep going.
Yeah.
Step four, now the shepherd takes the wolf and brings it over the river leaving the sheep
behind.
Excellent! I think you are on the right track.
Yep!
And finally, step five, he goes back and brings the sheep over the river.
And that's it! I solved it!
You solved it!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Wow! Awesome!
Guys! You're really great!
You're so good! Congratulations!
Wow! That is so cool!
You only beat me! Good job! Keep going!
Hey, I'd really love to hang out some more with you, but it's getting late and we really have to go now
Yeah, I hope we'll see each other again. Bye. Yeah. Bye. Thanks for stopping by. See you guys
We are the smartest guards in the whole wild world
Yo, we are we truly are
man
That was exhausting
It's time for a nice hot cup of Brazilian coffee
make that two sure I'll bring you one they've got an awful lot of coffee in
Brussels oops this is the way they went yes and I've been following their tracks
and they are leading right this way we we could at least have taken one of the
torches with us it's so dark I can't see anything ah don't worry I'm a cat a
feline knows is one of the most sensitive things on earth I can smell
our enemies clearly and as long as I don't lose the track we will find them
trust me what a relief oh this wasn't necessary
Mika lead on why do we have to go I don't know I lost my sense of smell okay
so that's what you get when you can let a girl navigate now step aside and let
the man handled this all we have to do is follow the wind because if there is
one coming from a tunnel there must be an exit on the other side I saw this on
television you mean we have to go chase your fart
don't be so cynical folks right for a change yes I am now follow me hmm that's
strange this tunnel has a metal floor yeah and it's getting steeper and
steeper what is it Laurie is is everyone alright oh I'm here I'm here oh I wonder
where the slight dump does I don't know but it feels like we are still moving
we're going to die the name of Lionel's father we should be proud of ourselves
shooting with them all be careful what you say we didn't force you to come with
us feel free to jump if you want to shut up you two this is neither the right
place nor the right time for discussion no I kept my mouth shut long enough this
is precisely the right time for discussions Lionel I need to have a word
with you about you and your father it can't go on like this
Oh my god, it's going to die!
Oh, Lionel, listen to me. We all know you made mistakes in the past, but sometimes you
just have to put your past behind you. We've been going all the way with you here, and
something is really...
Hey, look, I see a light at the end of the tunnel!
What?
Yes, I see it, too! We are safe!
Oh, wait, it's coming closer!
Yes, it's coming closer way too fast!
That's not the exit! It's a train!
Mika, I'm sorry but I completely forgot what you were about to say.
You wanted to tell me something about my father. Now tell me, I'm listening.
Alright. I said, we all know you made mistakes in the past.
Hey! Come on, get to the point!
I was just about getting to the point!
Stop shouting!
I'm not shouting! I'm screaming!
For heaven's sake, just tell me what you wanted to say, preferably before we all die!
I just wanted to say that I know that you made mistakes like this and...
Please keep your poor feet until it's at the bank, let all chat.
We must get the two halves together again.
Grab for his tail.
Okay.
I'll go grab a mouse.
now pull okay one two three are you all right
high heels anymore all right no before anything else gets in the way
Lionel it can't go on like this we've been going all the way with you and
something is very obvious about the relationship between you and your father
but you have to realize that it is over now this let me tell you something about
when I was little my mother had to work all day so I was home alone all the time
Ahh!
We are the pirates!
Pirates!
Oh, man, they're coming.
I guess it was dark, though.
They're going to kill me!
Recharge fire!
Okay, okay, that was close. Aim higher.
Aye, captain.
And... fire again!
Ahh!
Cassians, we've got to stop this thing!
Ah, stop it!
Be my guest.
Let me to the front here.
Okay, okay, it's been a while.
Where are the brakes?
This must be the brakes.
Okay, wait a minute. This one here.
Brakes!
One more try, okay?
Okay.
Come to traffic professional navigation system.
Please wait while loading.
Locating vehicle.
Destination found.
The Temple of Dinuwot.
Distance to destination one kilometer.
Cool.
Hey, that's pretty cool.
Put me on the right track all along.
I knew it.
I knew I could do the right thing.
Distance to destination 500 meters.
Uh, Laurie, don't you think we're going pretty fast?
Hey, the faster we go, the sooner we'll be there.
Distance to destination 300 meters.
Oh, Lionel, did your father mention this in his book?
Uh, if he did, I obviously didn't get the clue because I don't remember.
Distance to destination, 200 meters.
Yay! We're almost there!
Then watch, here we come!
Guys, I've got a very bad feeling about this.
Warning! Warning!
End of tracks in 100 meters.
What?!
We have arrived!
You have reached your destination.
Thank you for being an incredible professional.
Congratulations. Is everyone alive?
Okay, I think I'll need a moment to recover.
Mika, didn't you want to tell me something? Now is the chance.
Did I? Oh, never mind.
Look, we found it. This must be the entrance to the temple of Dunawat.
Yes, indeed. I remember the drawing in the diary.
So this is our goal. But what are we supposed to do here?
How about going inside?
Inside?
No, actually we got chased around the world by the music Gestapo,
kicked out of a plane, ran over by rolling stones and nearly eaten by wooden people just to turn around and go home.
Not!
You can jump into a lake if you want to, but I'll go with Lionel.
And so will I.
But, but, that's not what I...
You don't have to come if you don't want to, Laurie.
This is something between my father and me.
Oh, no way!
We will stick with you until the end, won't we?
Yeah.
Let's go and kick some ass. Come on, Laurie.
Okay, let's go.
Lionel, you go first.
I don't think it's a good idea to just walk inside.
Don't forget, we're hopelessly outnumbered.
Wait here, if I go alone maybe they won't notice me. I'll take a look around the corner and check out the situation.
Dear comrades, the time has come. History is about to be made. From this day on there will be no other producers than us.
With all sources of inspiration, under our control, we will be able to control all music on this planet.
Unlimited wealth. Unprecedented increase in shareholder value. The ultimate return on investment.
Gentlemen, power up the amplifiers. Let's...
My producer, it is done.
There's no inspiration left.
Yes. Yes. Very good. Very, very good.
Now it's time to celebrate!
Oh no! Oh no, it's too late!
What? What did you see?
The source of inspiration!
They destroyed it! We came too late!
Oh shit!
Oh no! Is there really nothing we can do?
We must stop them!
Oh, get out of my way!
Nobody messes with Mika!
I will walk right in there and kick those guys' butts into next Monday!
No, no, no!
Let me go! Let me go!
Mika! Mika!
It's pointless!
What?
Mika, it's pointless!
The source has already been destroyed!
Don't tell me you're giving up!
You're the big thinker!
Though think of something already!
If not for us, do it for your father!
Alright.
Let's give it one last try.
Okay guys.
What do we have?
Well, well, we have the diary.
No, Laurie, I lost it when I crashed into the forest, sorry.
Oh, well, then, I guess we don't have anything else.
Except, except, maybe, but I guess it doesn't mean anything.
Except for what? What do you have? Anything might be important.
Show it to us, Laurie.
I, I found this stone egg in a cavern in the jungle.
It seemed to be unimportant, so I didn't mention it.
You found one of those too?
I have another one and it just looks the same.
It makes a different sound.
Yeah.
Guys, I think I must tell you something.
Yes, Poke?
Well, look what I found.
This can't be a coincidence.
And each of them makes a different sound.
Is this another puzzle?
Let's see what happens when we let them play together.
That's a good idea.
The tune sounds familiar to me, but where do I know it from?
This sounds really beautiful.
Yeah, it sounds like the music of a second-class porn movie.
No, it does not!
What, you watch porn?
Oh, Ly-
No!
Lionel, do you know this melody?
It's nothing more than a faded memory from long ago.
It sounds like a song my father used to sing to me when I was little.
your father used to sing porn soundtracks try to remember it it might
be important ah well I think I think it went like this let's call to battle on a
new social scale to song and throw dance I don't know spooky try it again but
this time keep singing this is how then you think I can't barely remember the
song I'll try hmm let's call to battle on a
musical scale through songs and so dance the good will prevail the power of music
in its true form of art
From a package, no, it comes from the hall.
At last.
That was about time.
What took you so long?
Wait a minute.
You're not the high priest.
And you, you're not the master of ceremonies.
Yes, and you are not Santa Claus.
Tell us something we don't know.
You don't know who I am?
I've been alive since time began.
Not beast, not god, yet not man.
I am the music and the dance.
I'm the piper who enchants.
My name is Poke.
My teeth are shiny.
I turn off the girls so they can kiss my poke.
That is the strangest welcome I've ever received.
Times must have changed a lot more than I thought.
All right, let me put it succinctly.
My name is Heather, and I am the spirit of inspiration.
And by the tritones, it's been ages since someone called me finally and summoned me here.
The last source of inspiration has been destroyed five minutes ago. I was there. So tell me who you really are.
Inspiration can never be destroyed. It's one of the forces that binds the universe together.
You mean like duct tape?
What? What are you talking about?
I really am the spirit of inspiration.
Know me.
How could the people survive without inspiration?
This ritual has been passed down from generation to generation.
And you have the three keys.
And you know the song to open the gate to my dimension.
And now you tell me you don't know who I am?
I'm sorry to say this, but no, who are you?
I already told you.
And I wish I knew what was going on.
Have people forgotten about me?
Long ago, they used to summon me every week.
We used to sing and dance and our hearts and minds would soar.
Those were the days.
But then the summonings became fewer and fewer
and eventually stopped altogether.
I can't remember how long and for centuries
I've waited lonely and restless
until finally you called me.
This couldn't be a coincidence.
Well, getting together, singing and dancing,
this has become rare lately.
Really, how so?
Music is not free anymore.
All the music there is being controlled
by the big corporations.
I have the full power to decide what kind of music is made, who may listen to it and what the price is.
We even had to pay a license fee to be allowed to sing happy birthday for Lionel the other day.
Lionel's father had discovered why those corporations could become so powerful.
Nobody knew that there were actual sources of inspiration hidden all over the world,
which all creative people in the world were drawing from.
The music corporations found out about them and destroyed all of them, except one, which remained hidden.
My father quit his musical career after he found out about this last source of inspiration in order to save it.
But he was too old to finish what he started.
He wrote down all his findings in his book and coded in a way only I could decipher.
decipher we followed the lead but we came too late the last source of
inspiration was destroyed before my eyes tell me what exactly was it that you saw
what did it look like well it looked like a sparkling fountain brilliantly
glowing in a bright light I see there's really not much of the
ancient knowledge left is there anymore I'll tell you what you've seen what
What you've seen is a fountain of inspiration.
But where do you think that inspiration comes from?
I mean, inspiration is like spring water.
It's fresh and it's new.
And even though it is fresh and new,
it's not being produced by anything or in any way.
Like spring water, what you see as spring water
is actually just bend the rain in the hills
that's come down.
and inspiration is is like that spring water it's it's a very part of yourself and everyone else
what you saw being destroyed that's just merely an outlet i mean it's it's like the well you know
it's not where the water is made it's just a place where it surfaces i am the spirit that brings
inspiration to the surface uh so so you're taking all bad ideas that went down the toilet and turned
them into inspirational spring water no i mean yes no is he always like this
so that means there is still hope and and what about the bad guys
yeah there's still a bunch of bad guys on the temple musically piercing into
your fountain what yes it's the producer and his
minions you mean those are the people who
drained all my fountains yes that's them all right now watch listen closely i'm going to show you
how to deal with guys like this fancy pants producer what are you doing in my temple
who are you i am the owner of this fountain and i don't tolerate any unwanted guests
in here now the fountains of inspiration will be refilled and music will be free
again no never I've worked all my life to get to this point and I will not let
you ruin it I'm your session supposed to earn their
money by putting up a tip jar let me tell you this your tip jar belongs to us
Because we are the ones making people like you successful.
We know what the consumers want.
Because we make consumers want it.
How are you going to do that with inspiration?
Minions, adjust the speakers.
Turn up the amplifiers.
ATTACK!
Who's motherfucker?
I can make you say, who's motherfucker?
You say, who's motherfucker?
Who's motherfucker?
For my real life, I say, who's motherfucker?
That's the way you act.
Soon before it's too late.
Never be forgotten, because our music is our intellectual property.
And we can release the same songs again and again for every generation.
We're making sure only a fraction of all the music ever made is legally available.
So there is always a market that is never saturated.
Isn't this wonderful?
You want music to be free?
Only over my dead body!
Minions, get ready to fire!
Attack!
to practice this and it was wonderful.
And next to me is the son, Risa Manis Finn.
I'd very much like to thank you, Finn,
for taking up all the stuff Sefiro couldn't do
and just saying, okay, we're going to pull this through.
I will take up the jobs,
additionally to the jobs I had to make.
Thank you very much.
And finally, Foxy, the lighting assistant.
Some persons that were in the comic book because we didn't know it would work out until the very last minute.
I hope they are here. And it is Taipoo. Taipoo, are you here? Come over! Come over!
He wrote the ending song! We have to see ladies here.
It performed the song and made the playback for Hitler and she played it. She sung it. Wow.
This round would not be complete without the person who draws the strings, who makes them dance.
The mighty producer Cheetah!
You know, to him we're like just puppets, you know?
Alright, I'm running out of words here, so all I've done is wish everyone a nice day.
Thank you for being with us. Dance is going to take place. Yes, we're a little bit delayed.
But we are going as fast as we can to set up the dance here with our favorite DJ Big Blue Fox.